bradfordexchangechecks.com 2009-06-20

# Bradford Exchange Checks Privacy Policy

Secure Ordering

Shopping online at bradfordexchangechecks.com is extremely safe. Bradford Exchange Checks® uses secure Application Servers to protect your ordering information as it comes to us via the Internet. This means that all information you enter in the checkout section of our online store is encrypted. This includes the name, address, checking account information, bank information and credit card number you provide. VeriSign provides authentication that you are in direct communication with bradfordexchangechecks.com.

If you have any concerns about ordering electronically, please call (800) 323-8104 to place your order over the phone (Se Habla Español). 2-box minimum and processing fee apply for phone orders.

Privacy Policy

Bradford Exchange Checks is part of the Bradford Group of companies. We at the Bradford Group are committed to protecting our customers' privacy. We know that you are concerned about how your information is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. The following notice describes our privacy policy.

Automatic Anonymous Information:

This is information provided by cookies. Cookies are small alphanumeric identifier files that store information. They enable our systems to recognize your browser and computer, and to provide important features that personalize our site to make your shopping faster and easier. For example cookies store your shopping cart selection information between your visits. Cookie information is anonymous, meaning that it does not tell us who owns or uses the computer on which the cookies are stored.

You can prevent your browser from accepting cookies through its help feature, but that prevents you from shopping on our site. We recommend that you take full advantage of all the features we've designed to make shopping easy and fun.

Information That We Collect From Every Visitor:

We collect anonymous information from cookies about the site pages, items, stores, and articles you view. This is not combined with personal information from your account with us, but is used as aggregate statistical information (group information) that helps us learn more about how people use and react to our site.

We may send anonymous cookie information to Coremetrics and other companies that provide services to us. These service providers do not have any right to use the information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us. None of the information we send to these service providers is personally identifiable, meaning that it does not include name, email or street address information of any individual. If you would like to change your settings or opt out of the Coremetrics service, please click here.

Information You Give Us:

When you place an item in your shopping cart, we store that information so that your cart selections are not lost between visits. 

When you place an order, we will need your name, phone number, e-mail address, mailing address, checking account information, bank information, credit card number and expiration date so that we can process and contact you about the order. We will keep a record of this information and the items you purchase. This allows us to process and fulfill your orders and return requests, and to send you information that's of interest. We provide necessary customer contact information to service providers who fulfill your orders and send our mailings to you. They are not permitted to use your information for any other purpose.

Periodically, Bradford Exchange Checks may invite customers to participate in contests and surveys. If you participate, the information we collect may be associated with your account, and used to improve your overall customer experience.

E-mail:

When you place an order, or have a customer service request, we send you an e-mail to confirm that we received your request or to answer your inquiry. These messages are generated automatically, and are sent regardless of "no-e-mail" requests. If you prefer not to receive other types of e-mail, you can indicate your preference when you receive an e-mail from us. We have an opt-out feature on every e-mail that we mail out. Or, you can respond to an e-mail and request to be removed. You can also use the contact us feature on our site or phone us at (800) 323-5577 to let us know that you prefer not to receive offers by e-mail. Information Sharing: Please remember that if you add or change e-mail addresses, you will need to separately notify us about your e-mail preferences for each such address.

Information Sharing:

Bradford Exchange Checks is part of a network of companies who specialize in various high quality interest-based products such as checks, collector plates, dolls, figurines, ornaments and music boxes. Our affiliated companies include:

  * The Bradford Exchange

  * The Ashton-Drake Galleries

  * Ardleigh Elliott & Sons

  * Hamilton Collection

  * Van Hygan & Smythe

  * Hawthorne Village

  * Bradford Editions

  * StudioHummel

  * Hamilton Authenticated

  * Collectibles Today

We share information about your purchases with these affiliates, and on occasion you may receive offers mailed by post or e-mail from our affiliates for other products that we believe you may enjoy. We share certain collections of personal information that we regard as non-sensitive with selected third parties, such as mailing list brokers and database marketers. These entities may collect and use the information alone or in combination with customer information supplied by other companies, and share it with other companies for marketing purposes in the form of mailing lists. Our contracts with such third parties prohibit them from using or permitting use of the information we provide to generate reports about specific individuals, and require that they honor our customers' do-not-call, do-not-mail, and do-not-email requests when our information is used. We occasionally do list exchanges in which we provide mailing lists containing certain customers name and contact information to third parties in exchange for mailing lists with such information concerning the other company's customers. From time to time we may use your personal information to send you offers that may interest you on behalf of third parties. If you respond to a third party offer you receive from us or from a company that has used a mailing list generated from our customer information, you will become that business's customer and the personal information you voluntarily submit to it will be subject to that company's privacy policy, not ours.

If you object to our sharing information about you as a customer with these affiliated and non-affiliated companies, or if you prefer not to receive postal mail or e-mail from us or other companies, you may use the contact us feature on our site, or phone us at (800) 323-5577 to tell us about your preferences.

Even if you opt out from information sharing generally, we must share information about your individual orders with the sister corporation that bills your purchases and stores your information, and with outside companies on a confidential basis as needed to obtain approval to charge your credit card, and to verify your address information. We also must share your name, address, bank, and checking account information with John H. Harland Company, the company that prints and mails your checks to you. The John H. Harland Company and its affiliates may store this information for use in processing re-orders and for other purposes, but neither it nor its affiliates are permitted to contact you in any way beyond what is needed to deliver your order. They are prohibited from offering you products or services via e-mail or postal mail, and from disclosing information about you or your order to third parties, except as necessary to deliver your order.

When you visit our website from a link on another website, or in an ad or e-mail, a cookie will be placed on your computer, and if you make a purchase, anonymous information may be provided to the referring website. This information is not personally identifiable. This will occur even if you opt out from other types of information sharing.

We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law; enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Bradford Exchange Checks, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection, collecting unpaid purchase balances, and reducing credit risks. This protects you from price increases related to uncollected debt.

Our business referral program is provided by an outside company. If you choose to use this optional service, then they may share your information with us, but are not authorized to contact you or provide your information to others without your permission.

Children:

bradfordexchangechecks.com is a shopping site for mature collectors. We do not knowingly solicit data from, or market to, children under age 13.

Customer Information Transfer:

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses and assets, including customer information.

Visit Us Often:

Please visit this Privacy Policy frequently, as our business changes all the time, and we update this policy to reflect those changes. By visiting our site you agree that we may collect and use information as stated in our privacy policy. If we change our privacy policy, we will post the changes on this page so you are always informed about what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
